## **Bharti Patel**

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

#### CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

## **TOOLS**

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8 Zeplin

## **SKILLS**

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Visual design

#### EDUCATION

#### **General Assembly**

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Commercial Arts
Nirmala Niketan, India

## CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

#### PROFILE

I'm a Designer with a passion for creativity. I believe that simplicity is the ultimate sophistication – that less is more. I have an extensive background in graphic design, web design, and advertising. I bring my experience, passion, and professionalism to any creative task.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Sr. UX/UI Designer - Apex IT, Remote July 2021 - Present

- Working as an in-house Sr. UX/UI Consultant at Apex IT, a global consulting firm that provides award-winning services to transform the customer, employee, and student experiences.
- Produce concept briefs and prototypes while collaborating with Principal consultants and various stockholders.
- Provide a full range of design solutions to various Apexit clients across the country following standard design principles.

## UX Designer - The Michaels Companies, Inc, Remote Mar 2020 - July 2020

- Working with the E-comm team for Michaels.com and native app on improving user experience.
- Produced concept briefs and prototypes and UX designs while collaborating with engineering and product management.
- Worked on curbside pickup, checkout streamline & shipping options concept designs by conducting market research and competitive landscape analyses.

## UX / UI Designer - SJSU, San Jose, CA Aug 2019 - Sep 2019

- Worked with the team as UX/Visual/UI designer for creating a new advanced analytics platform.
- Worked on landing page and other page designs to make it more simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material following SJSU brand guidelines.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

## UX / UI Designer - Cisco Systems, San Jose, CA Jul 2018 - Oct 2018

- Worked with the team as UX/UI designer for the web application, determining best UX solutions based on customer feedback & business goals. Identifying challenges and adapting as needed based on the context of the solution and customer.
- Created pixel-perfect mocks to communicate user flows and interaction and visual designs. Delivered redline specs for development following
   Cisco brand quidelines.
- Collaborated with PMs, developers & engineers from conception to early implementation establishing timelines and consensus from all parties around product flow.

## UX/UI Designer - 12 Digit Marketing, Redwood City, CA Jun 2017 - Oct 2017

- Worked with a team to improve UI and providing the right solution to the interface and, delivering pixel perfect mockups for development.
- Producing mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.
- Worked with Client Service Manager/Marketing with visual designs for Retail/Brand creative campaigns delivering responsive designs.

## UX Designer & Visual Designer - Cisco Systems, San Jose, CA Jan 2017 - May 2017

- Worked as one of the UX designer & Visual Designer for Cisco VTS (Virtual Topology Systems) product.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user-friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated with service provider customers like Version and Turk Cell.
- Worked on the Visuals for VTS poster using the personas, for marketing the product., using brand guidelines.
- Produced mockups and prototypes while iterating with engineering and
- Product management to meet feature requirements for the existing product.

## **Bharti Patel**

UX Designer with background in Visual & Advertising

#### CONTACT

- **(**510) 221-8063
- bhartip0703@gmail.com
- Fremont, CA
- in linkedin.com/in/bharti7
- bhartiux.github.io

#### **TOOLS**

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch 3 InVision Axure MS Office Oracle Webcenter Axure RP 8 Zeplin

### **SKILLS**

User research
User personas
Data synthesis
Rapid prototype
Information architecture
Usability testing
Wireframes
Visual design

#### EDUCATION

#### General Assembly

San Francisco, CA
User Experience Design
Immersive program crafted
by top practitioners in the field
-10 weeks Full time
Commercial Arts
Nirmala Niketan, India

#### CERTIFICATION

Academy X - Web Design Santa Clara, CA Learn IT - Computer Graphics San Mateo, CA

#### **EXPERIENCE**

\*\*\* Was preparing for her UX design course during this period Jan 2016 – Mar 2016 \*\*\*

## UX Designer - San Francisco Bicycle Coalition (SFBC) March 2016 - April 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an mobile app that allows SFBC members to communicate and share with each other.
- User interviews, survey, competitive & comparative analysis, user flow, site maps,
- concept model, and wireframes. Usability testing drove the design of the prototype.

# UX Designer - Progress Hardware - Ecommerce website March 2016 (as part of General Assembly)

- 2-weeks project to design an ecommerce website that helps to find right tool
  for loyal customers who don't like to go to stores, through detailed reviews,
  update inventory & same day shipping option.
- Used stakeholder interviews, competitive and comparative analysis, card sorting, and usability testing to inform design of global navigation as well as search and check out flows.

#### Web / Visual Designer - Ross Stores Inc. Dublin, CA Oct 2013 - Dec 2015

- Researched & redesigned intranet portal using Adobe Creative suite & Oracle Webcenter.
- Created meaningful and compelling designs to help users become more productive and frequently visit the portal.
- Worked on design to be simpler and user friendly from complex and abstract material.
- Collaborated extensively across department & with various stakeholders.

\*\*Freelance Projects\*\*

#### Web Designer - Drishticon, Fremont, CA Dec 2014 - Mar 2015

- Worked with owner & developers to improve the UI & Visuals of their current website.
- Recreated the current logo & the banners using Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop.

## Graphic/ Web Designer - Infinilytics Inc, Santa Clara, CA May 2013 - Jul 2013

- Designed marketing and promotional materials across email, mobile, web, print, and social media.
- Created branding materials logo creation and reconstruction.
- Assisted others with layout and design worked with the marketing department to improve the final product.

## Project Manager - United Way SML, Fremont, CA Mar 2009 - May 2009

- Worked as a project manager for redesigning the website for United Way Sonoma Mendocino Lake.
- Responsible for total needs of the client including management of technical and creative resource to deliver complete corporate- quality branding and web solutions.

## Web Designer - Ondemandtek, Fremont, CA Jan 2009 - Mar 2009

- Worked with various design tools including Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash to implement web designs and functionality
- Created Logo using Adobe illustrator.